Modern advertising is saturated
现代广告充满了
with humanistic sloganeering.
人本主义的口号
And what do I mean by that?
什么意思？
Like Nike, “Just do it.”
像是耐克，“尽管做吧”
[Nike, L'Oreal and Me]
耐克、欧莱雅和我
What does that mean, ‘Just do it’?
这句标语想要宣扬什么呢？
It implies there is some conscience you have,
意味着，你有一些道德心
some self–restraint,
也会自我克制
an internal process you go through
在决定做某事的时候
before you decide to do something.
内心会有挣扎
They’re saying, “Don’t listen to it, don’t think about it,
而他们说，"别听它的，不要想它
just do it!”
尽管做吧！"
Why?
为什么
I have a series of ads that answer this question.
有一系列的广告都能回答这个问题
So, Nike makes that proposal, who gives the answer?
耐克提议了以后，谁给了回应？
L’Oreal, “Because I’m worth it.”
欧莱雅
Why should I just do it?
为什么尽管做吧？
Because I’m worth it, that’s why.
因为我值得拥有
But of all the ads I ever saw,
但是在我看过的所有广告中
the most blatant,
最明目张胆的
naked assertion of humanistic sloganeering
赤裸裸地叫嚣人本主义的
was from a company whose slogan was,
是一家公司，口号说
“Total indulgence. Zero guilt.”
“放纵无罪”
It was about Weight Watchers.
这是一家减肥中心
It doesn’t matter what it was about,
经营什么没关系
but they had the audacity to make that their slogan,
但是他们竟敢这样宣称
“Total indulgence. Zero guilt.”
“放纵无罪”
No conscience, just indulge without conscience.
没有道德心，只有恣意没有良知
Who does things without conscience?
如果丧失了良知会怎么样？
Generally, they’re called animals.
通常来说，动物才会如此
The animals, they’re not crying
动物在啃食其它动物的幼崽时
they’re not stopping to think,
并不会停下来想
“Oh, these babies are so cute, why should we do this?”
噢，这些小幼仔很可爱，为什么要吃掉它们呢？
Never.
它们从不这样考虑
There was a YouTube video recently, where they say,
最近在Youtube 上有段视频
“After this lioness killed a deer,
母狮扑杀了一头鹿
and then it took the calf”, and all the people went,
之后叼走了一头鹿仔
“Yes, and after playing with it for a while,
“那只是跟猫一样带回去玩耍
as cats do, she’ll eat it.
之后就吃掉
They’ll kill it and offer it to her children.”
杀了喂孩子。”
So, a lack of conscience; of considering
缺乏良知，自制
why we do things; self–restraint;
不去考虑为什么要做这些事情
what Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn called
亚历山大 ·索尔仁尼琴
in his famous “World Split Apart” address,
在他著名的讲演《割裂的世界》里说
“What is needed is serene voluntary self–restraint.”
“我们需要自愿自我克制，并怡然自得”
Serene voluntary self–restraint.
自我克制，怡然自得
That’s interesting.
有意思
You could say that’s the definition of tapasyā.
你可能会说那是苦行
As Śrīla Prabhupād used to say,
圣帕布帕德
and has in his Bhāgavatam purport,
在《薄伽梵歌原义》的注释中说过
“What is tapasyā?
什么是苦行？
Voluntarily inconveniencing oneself
“为了实现灵性觉醒
for the sake of spiritual realisation.”
而自愿接受磨难”
You will be inconvenienced by living in this world.
你会在这个世界接受很多磨练
We will have to suffer by living in this world,
活在世上就会受苦
it’s inevitable, it’s unavoidable,
这是不可避免，无可回避的
but a spiritually progressive person
但是一个追求灵性成长的人
will voluntarily inconvenience themselves,
会自愿的“磨练”自己
will voluntarily undergo certain types of “suffering”
为了灵性的进步
for the sake of spiritual advancement.
他们愿意接受特别的"苦难"